Rachel L. Deckard

Indianapolis, IN 46237 | (317) 590-1065 | rachelleedeckard@gmail.com Website | https://rachelleedeckard.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/

Summary

Dedicated and driven individual with an extensive history in customer service and sales. University student currently studying Web Programming. Previous enrollment at Eleven Fifty Academy for Microsoft .NET and JavaScript. Many years of experience in multiple leadership and management roles. Formal education in esthetics, color theory, art, and design. Currently seeking new career opportunities as a Junior Web Developer.

Core Competencies

- C# (Beginner)
- Git (Beginner)
- GitHub (Beginner)
- Unit Testing (Beginner)
- Visual Studio (Beginner)
- JavaScript (Beginner)
- Agile Development (Beginner)

- Python (Beginner)
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) (Proficient)
- HTML (Proficient)
- Microsoft Office (Proficient)
- Google Workspace (Proficient)
- Photoshop (Proficient)
- Illustrator (Proficient)

Education

Vincennes University | Web Programming Certificate | Expected Graduation December 2021

Eleven Fifty Academy | JavaScript Gold Badge | December 2019

Eleven Fifty Academy | Microsoft .NET Gold Badge | September 2019

Experience

Front Desk Receptionist | Eye Surgeons of Indiana | August 2019 to January 2021

- Manage check in and check out window and input patient's demographics into EMR.
- Check insurance eligibility and accept payments for visits and product.
- Balancing money batches at end of day and managing cash draw.
- Creating and implementing Operation Manual for front office staff.

Key-Holder | SalonCentric | November 2017 to November 2019

- Day to day operations including opening, closing, shipment, and assisting customers.
- Informing clients of the latest brands and tools to help them build their business.
- Promote classes for continuing education.
- Mange money drawers, deposits, and change orders.

Assistant Store Manager | Talbots | May 2015 to October 2017

- Creating reports and documenting store metrics and payroll.
- Handling everyday store operational activities and store productivity.
- Coaching team about individual growth and assisting them with their client books and client relationship.
- Maintaining and executing any visual merchandising.
- Partnering with district on operational projects and traveling with District Operational Manager.

Acting Store Manager | Talbots | September 2016 to February 2017

- Developing a strong team that provides our guest with a unique, personal experience.
- Creating schedule and maintaining payroll every month as well as other store manager duties.
- Leading the team to success through listening, inquiring, and inspiring.
- Manage closing of location and transfer of product and supplies from closure.